trustedwatch.com 2019-01-11

# References - Privacy Policy - TrustedWatch - the international timepiece portal

Anzeige

The controller as defined by data protection laws, particularly the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), is:

TrustedWatch GmbH  
Heilbronner Str. 30  
D - 74223 Flein  
Tel: 0049 (0)7131-797120  
E-Mail: info@trustedwatch.de

## Your rights as a data subject

You may exercise the following rights at any time using the contact information provided for our data protection officer:

  * Information about your personal data we have stored and their processing,
  * Rectification of incorrect personal data,
  * Erasure of your personal data we have stored,
  * Restriction of processing if we are not yet permitted to delete your data due to legal obligations,
  * Object against your data being processed by you, and
  * Data portability if you have consented to data processing or concluded a contract with us.

If you have given your consent, you may revoke it at any time with future effect.

You may at any time lodge a complaint with your competent supervisory authority. Your competent supervisory authority is based on the state in which you reside, your field of work, or the alleged infringement. You will find a list of supervisory authorities (for the private sector) with addresses at: <https://www.bfdi.bund.de/DE/Infothek/Anschriften_Links/anschriften_links-node.html>.

## Purpose of data processing by the controller and third parties

We only process your personal data for the purposes stated in this privacy policy. Your personal data will not be transmitted to third parties for any other purposes than stated. We only share your personal data with third parties:

  * with your express consent,
  * processing is necessary for performance of a contract with you,
  * processing is necessary to comply with a legal obligation,

processing is necessary on the grounds of legitimate interests and there is no reason to assume you have an overriding legitimate interest in your data not being shared.

## Erasure or blocking of data

We comply with the principles of data reduction and data economy. We therefore only store your personal information as long as it is necessary for the purposes stated herein or according to the file retention periods required by law. Once no longer required for the respective purpose or after expiry of these periods the respective data is routinely blocked and erased in accordance with the law.

## Personal data collected when visiting our website

When visiting our website, a cookie will automatically collect general information. This information (server log files) for example include the type of web browser, the operating system used, the domain name of your internet service provider, and similar. These are only information which do not allow you to be identified.

This information is technically necessary to correctly deliver the website contents requested by you and are required to use the internet. They will particularly be processed for the following purposes:

  * ensure a good website connection,
  * ensure trouble-free use of our website,
  * analysing system security and stability, as well as
  * for additional administrative purposes.

The processing of your personal data is based on our legitimate interest in the above purposes of data collection. Your data will not be used to identify you. This data will only be received by the controller and, where necessary, the processor.

Anonymous information of this type may be statistically analysed by us to optimise our internet presence and the technology used.

## Cookies

Like many other websites we also use so-called 'cookies'. Cookies are small text files transferred from a website server to your hard drive. It automatically provides us with specific data such as IP address, browser and operating system used, and your internet connection.

Cookies cannot be used to launch programs or transmit viruses to a computer. The information from cookies allows us to make our website easier for you to navigate and display our website correctly.

The data collected by us will never be shared with third parties or merged with personal information without your consent.

Of course you can on principle also view our website without cookies. Internet browsers are typically configured to accept cookies. Generally speaking you can disable the use of cookies at any time by changing your browser settings. Please use the help function of your internet browser to learn how to change these settings. Please note that blocking cookies may prevent some functions of our website from working.

## Contact form

When contacting us with any requests by e-mail or using the contact form, you voluntarily consent for contact purposes. This requires providing a valid e-mail address. This is used to allocate the enquiry and to process said. Any other data is optional. The information provided by you will be stored to process your enquiry and for any follow-up questions. Once your enquiry has been completed the personal data is automatically deleted.

## Use of Matomo

This website uses Matomo (formerly Piwik), an open-source software for the statistical evaluation of visitor access. Matomo uses so-called "cookies", which are text files that are stored on your computer and allow an analysis of your use of the website.

The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website is stored on a server in Germany.

The IP address is anonymized immediately after processing and prior to its storage. You have the option to prevent the installation of cookies by changing the settings of your browser software. We point out that with appropriate settings not all functions of this website may be available.

You can decide whether a unique web analytics cookie may be stored in your browser in order to allow the operator of the website to collect and analyze various statistical data.

## Changes to our privacy policy

We reserve the right to change this privacy policy to ensure it always complies with current legal requirements or to apply changes in our services to our privacy policy, e.g. when introducing new services. The new privacy policy will then apply when you return to our website.

## Questions about data protection

If you have questions about data protection, please e-mail us or contact our company’s data protection officer directly:

datenschutz@trustedwatch.de

## Watch consignment

Our website includes a watch consignment option, which allows you to offer your watch to watch retailers anonymously after providing your name and your e-mail address along with information about your watch. Only the data related to the watch will be shared with our registered watch dealers. Then can then submit an offer if interested. After 10 days you will receive all offers submitted by the dealers along with contact information. The data provided by you will not be merged with other day we [may](http://www.trustedwatch.biz/en?s=search&hersteller=MAY) collect through other components on our website.

Welcome to TrustedWatch GmbH. The TrustedWatch GmbH is one of the leading media enterprise for the watch and jewellery sector in Europe. With its high-coverage portals and marketplaces in a variety of languages, and with an additional press distribution network direct to over 4,000 journalists, TrustedWatch is able to offer manufacturers, service providers and trading ventures in the watch and jewellery industry varied and precise to target advertising and advertising services. In addition, we offer TrustedWatch GmbH software solutions, marketing solutions and distribution solutions. These are widely known in the segment and enjoy excellent repute.

Are you interested? [Then learn more about our company here](http://www.trustedwatch.org/en/trustedwatch).

**Watch portal, watch magazine, watch market and watch TV**

Phone: +49 (0)7131-797120  
Fax: +49 (0)7131-797122
